2 0433 967 370 **2** admin@rasela.info in linkedin.com/in/rasela
https://rasela.info

Technical Lead I Software Architect I Backend Engineer

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Accomplished and talented Technical Lead / Software Architect supported by over seven years' experience working on various IT projects including leading a technical team of up to 18 on an acclaimed International Innovation awarded product. Experience includes forging and building partnerships, bridging communication gaps and leading and working with business and technical teams to drive stability, operational excellence and a culture of efficiency. Confident knowledge of Software Architecture Design and Development using microservice architecture with experience in data modelling, implementation of various Integration patterns and architecture styles, interface design, data mapping and orchestration. Hard-wired for continuous improvement with ample evidence of operational and leadership expertise to propel quality improvement projects supported by high level problem-solving ability to increase productivity, achieve competitive advantage and create customer value.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am seeking an affiliation with an organisation where my technical experience and skills can be fully utilised in achieving results in a professional environment of innovative thinking and best practice.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- Bachelor of Science in Engineering Honours Degree: University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka
- Degree of Master's in Business Administration: Cardiff Metropolitan University, UK

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer (OCAJP) Nov 2013
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Routing and Switching Nov 2010

SKILLS MATRIX

Methodology	Agile, SCRUM methodologies
Languages & Technologies	Java, Spring, Hibernate, NodeJS, express, NestJS, Typescript AWS – EC2, Load balancing, S3, CloudFront, Route53, RDS, Elasticache, Codebuild, Codedeploy Firebase, Heroku, Ghost, TravisCI, CircleCI, Bitbucket CI/CD
Database Software	MySQL, MS-SQL, MongoDB, Google FireStore
Tools & Packages	Atlasian JIRA, Bitbucket, SourceTree, Putty, mRemortNG, WinSCP, Postman, Jira, WinSCP, VMware, Virtual Box, Docker, Kubernates, Angular, Windows, Linux (Debian)
Software Design	Object Oriented Design (OOD)
Web Server	Tomcat, Nginx, Apache2
Library	STL, Crypto++, log4cpp
Debugging & Analysis	The GNU Project Debugger (GDB), Valgrind

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Architect	Millionspaces Inc	Jan 2019 – Current
Senior Technical Lead	Millionspaces Inc	Nov 2017 – Dec 2018
Technical Lead	Auxenta Inc	Mar 2016 – Oct 2017
Senior Software Engineer	Auxenta Inc	Mar 2014 – Feb 2016
Software Engineer / Release Manager	London Stock Exchange Group	Mar 2012 – Feb 2014

RASELA THARAKA

a 0433 967 370

№ admin@rasela.info

in linkedin.com/in/rasela
https://rasela.info

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Millionspaces

Oct 2017 - Current

Objective: To build a comprehensive solution and connect people with venue spaces while enabling them to search, book, pay and review suitable places.

Technologies: Java, Spring, NodeJS, NestJS, MySQL, AWS, Agile, Microservices

Role: Software Architect

Jan 2019 – Current

Using my comprehensive knowledge of software development technologies, I was responsible for the design, development and deployment architecture incorporating continuous development and continuous integration to power up the next-gen space booking platform for the Sri Lankan market.

Responsible For

- Engaging with various stakeholders to determine the design, technical standards, and coding applications
- Documenting and capturing information

Role: Senior Technical Lead

Nov 2017 - Dec 2018

In this role I was responsible for the overall planning, execution and success of software solutions to meet customer's needs by scoping requirements to the actual launch by leading a team of up to 20 consisting of the Backend development team, Frontend development team, Mobile development team and QA team.

Achievements: Millionspaces launched successfully for Sri Lankan market on November 2017.

Auxenta Inc Mar 2014 – Oct 2017

Profile: Auxenta Inc. is an innovative software engineering services and technology product consulting company.

Project: Questionnaire App (https://digitalstrategy.institute)

Client: Digital Strategy Institute

Objective: To design a mobile first hybrid web application with a feedback system to allow participants to partake in a survey at the end of each lecture to provide the Institute with a market insight of the participants.

Technologies: Angular 4, Firebase, Firestore, CircleCl

Role: Senior Technical Lead

I was responsible for leading the development team in support of the web/mobile technologies to ensure that the product behaves accordingly and displays the correct results in comparison charts.

Project: Assetminder (https://www.assetmindersolutions.co.uk/)

Objective: To develop a cloud-based fleet maintenance and workshop management SAAS based application system to support fleet maintenance and workshop planning and reduce administration, increase compliance, control costs and drive efficiencies throughout the transport fleet.

Technologies: Java EE, MySQL, Hibernate, Spring Framework, Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, RDS), Tomcat, Nginx, Jira, Source Tree, Putty, WinSCP, mRemortNG

Role: Technical Lead

I was responsible for providing leadership for leading a team of ten (10) consisting of a backend team, technical consultancy and software engineering team for the design and development application products for the web client and iOS/android mobile apps. The core modules include incident management, event management, defect management and vendor management. The Mobile application (iOS, Android) supports maximum usability using asynchronous data synchronization feature.

Achievements: Awarded the Innovation Award at the Fleet Transport Awards 2017.

RASELA THARAKA

2 0433 967 370 **2** admin@rasela.info in linkedin.com/in/rasela
https://rasela.info

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Auxenta Inc Mar 2014 – Oct 2017

Project: LexCheck (http://www.lexcheck.com/)

Objective: To overcome the arduous phases of legal contracting by increasing productivity and reducing legal costs using an Al-driven contracting platform involving artificial intelligence to automate and accelerate contract drafting, negotiations and reviews and extends to process various batch payment systems for complex commission matrices of different travel product/service providers including Airlines, Cruise companies etc.

Technologies: C#.NET, MS Word Add-In Libraries, WPF

Role: Senior Software Engineer

In this role I was responsible for planning and scheduling the software build and providing end-to-end business process consultancy and system solutions involving the configuration and development of an AI-driven contracting platform comprising of artificial intelligence. I was responsible for deploying the software release at different stages and environments.

Project: Local Bitcoin Bazaar

Objective: To develop a fully functional app to securely trade bitcoins via PayPal locally and internationally. **Technologies:** Java EE, MySQL, Hibernate, Spring Framework, Amazon Services (EC2, RDS), Tomcat, Jira, Source Tree, Putty, WinSCP, mRemortNG

Role: Software Engineer, Release Manager/System Engineer

Involved in the application development for iOS/Android platforms, fully fledged to support the complete trading lifecycle of the Local Bitcoin Bazaar product along with the supporting device verification, two factor authentication, SSL, map-based trading locations, notifications, peer messaging etc for crypto-currency enthusiasts. The trading step was well secured using interim wallet and confirmation from the both parties. The project went live in October 2015.

London Stock Exchange Group (LSEG) (MillenniumIT) Mar 2012 – Feb 2014 Projects:

- Clearing Gateway for Italian Derivatives Market
- Clearing Gateway for Turquoise/Oslo
- OBPriceFeeder: Platform migration Windows C# to Linux C++ and to develop an Underlying and Derivatives
 Price Feeder for Oslo Bors, Borsa Italiana Stock Exchange. Objective is to feed OM Secur system with latest price updates.

Technologies: C#, C++, STL, Crypto++, log4cpp, Linux (Debian), Netbeans, Visual Studio, eclipse, SVN, gcc, makefile, The GNU Project Debugger (GDB), Valgrind, Java, SQL, UML, Shell Scripting

Role: Software Engineer / Release Manager

I was responsible for building robust, scalable software as a key member of the engineering team, which included mentoring developers and delivering quality stable solutions following best practices and software guidelines suitable for continuous integration and deployment. I was also responsible for performing, maintaining, Bug Fixing, Change Request Implementation, Packaging, Releasing and 3rd level supporting for the mentioned projects.

Achievements: OBPriceFeeder went live on November 2013.

REFEREES

Available Upon Request